AKPE-USHIE, GRACE AKPANA

FCT Abuja, Nigeria | +2348128859226; 09036610859 | graceushie137@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Energetic and analytical accounting graduate with strong deductive reasoning and accounting skills. Excellent project management skills, coupled with strategic outlook and proven leadership ability in developing solutions to maintain the stability of the organization, a team worker willing to promote a friendly environment to aid an effective business environment. Accuracy in documenting transactional values, historical values as well as updating books of record with years' experience and training and the ability to use discretion with regards to confidential information.

EDUCATION

•	Bachelo	or of S	cience in A	ccounting (First Class Honours)
_				

Ecole Superieure de Commerce et d'administration (ESCAE) du Benin.

2021

West African Senior Certificate (WASSCE)

Depper Life High School, Calabar, Cross River State, Nigeria

2018

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION/CERTIFICATION

	,	
•	Institute of Chattered Accountancy (ICAN), Accounting Technician Scheme (ATS) Currently in	process
•	Certificate of Emotional Intelligence - (ESCAE) du Benin.	2021
•	Certificate of Graphic Design	2022
•	Certificate of Chattered Institute of Social Media and Digital Marketing	2023
•	Certificate of National Service	2023
•	Certification on the completion of the Sustainable Development Goals: The Goals, The Targets and Your Role-	2024
	(LEAP AFRICA)	

SKILLS AND CORE COMPETENCIES

_					
•	Auditing	•	Problem-Solving	•	Digital Skills
•	Quickbooks	•	System Analysis	•	Critical thinking
•	Payroll	•	Effective Communication Skills	•	Report Writing
•	Time Management	•	Active Listening	•	Artificial Intelligence
•	Documentation	•	Teamwork	•	Proposal Budget Preparation
•	Leadership Skills	•	Microsoft Skills		

WORK EXPERIENCE

Finance and Procurement Officer – Speak Out Africa Initiative Non-Governmental Organization, FCT, Abuja.

November

- 2023-Present
- Installation, Set-up and Preparation of Quickbooks.
- Budget Preparation for Proposals
- Proper Documentation of relevant documents in the organization.
- Proper recording of the Petty cash Reimbursement and Retirement monthly.
- Active preparation of the Payroll Account.
- Purchasing and Proper Documentation of the Organizational Assets.
- Preparation of Internal Memos in the organization.
- Streamlined the company's payroll activities by creating a new method of disbursement and using the quickbooks software.
- Analyzed information to improve my accounting, quickbooks and auditing skills.

Assistant Lecturer - College of Education, Ila-Orangun LGA, Osun State.

September 2022 - June 2023

- Providing full learning experience and support for undergraduate students by teaching and supervising students, maximizing students' performance, and inspiring students' interest.
- Created innovative teaching strategies to facilitate students' motivation and academic performance.
- Aided students to have knowledge about accountancy and major things to be noted in their pursuit to be accountants.

- Computing examination results of students in the department.
- Performing other administrative duties assigned by the University.

Courses Taught:

- Accounting Ethics
- Accounting Packages
- Accounting Theory
- Business Policy
- Cost Accounting
- Finance
- Principles Of Financial Accounting.

Enumeration Officer – INEC (Independent National Electoral Commission), Osun State.

Feb 2023 - March 2023

- Inquire about various specific information, including a person's name, age, religious preference, address and state of residency.
- Reviewed data gathered from interviews to check for completeness and accuracy
- Submitted completed tasks to supervisors and discussed developments frequently.
- Recognized and accounted for problems in obtaining data to develop strategies to improve results.

Assistant Accountant – HUMVIC Global Resources Limited, Port Harcourt, Rivers State.

June 2020 - August 2020

- Active management in keeping relevant documents in the organization.
- Assisted in proper documentation and recording of the books of accounts.
- Maintained schedules of accruals and adjusted entries accordingly
- Helped streamline the company's payroll activities by creating a new method of disbursement and using updated software.
- Analyzed information to aid my accounting skills improve.

INTEREST AND ACTIVITIES

- Documenting.
- Writing.
- Fluent French Writer and Speaker.
- Enjoy travelling.

REFRENCES

Available on Request.